Jeremy Jones

Nashville ♦ 615.480.7860 ♦ portfolio.jeremyjones.ninja ♦ banjeremy@gmail.com

Summary

Full stack developer with a passion for the front end. Agile, team player with over 4 years experience developing extraordinary apps, sites, and custom solutions. Fascinated with solving problems, and using the right tools for the job.

Experience

2-COM July, 2013 - Present

Senior developer on numerous client projects using a variety of technology stacks including ASP.Net MVC, Ruby on Rails, and AngularJS. Responsible for architecture, development, deployment, and maintenance.

Deloitte Consulting July, 2012 - July, 2013

Developer responsible for contributing to multiple simultaneous client projects. Wrote applications for various platforms, including mobile, web, and enterprise. Responsible for making technical and design decisions collaboratively in an agile environment.

University of Southern Mississippi August, 2010 - July, 2012 Research assistant responsible for developing several web-related research projects. Lead developer on a web-based graphics engine for simulation and training written in JavaScript and built using WebGL and Three.js.

Skills

JavaScript	Html5	Node.js	MongoDB	Agile
AngularJS	Jade	Ruby on Rails	Mongoose	TDD
jQuery	CSS/Less/Sass	ASP.Net MVC	PostgreSQL	Jasmine
Three.js	RWD	Cordova	SQL Server	Mocha

Education B

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of Southern Mississippi, May 2012

Accolades

Finalist at HackNashville6 on the NashvesTN project.

Expanded Work Experience

Software Developer, 2-COM July 2013 - Present

Lead software developer and architect. Oversee development and maintenance on public-facing marketing web sites. Design, build and maintain proprietary e-commerce solutions and product management system. Responsible for rearchitecting a legacy CMS.

Projects

YellaSource Brand Store (Current)

Create an online shopping experience for printed marketing materials designed for YellaWood contractors. Build an ecommerce platform using **Spree Commerce** and **Ruby on Rails**. Implement interactive customization features using **AngularJS**. Interface with legacy templating engine to generate pdfs.

ComTools API (Current)

Build a modern **JSON** API using **Web API 2** to expose product data for use with **Spree** ecommerce platform and generating customized printable marketing files dynamically.

Yanmar Tractor

Implemented responsive marketing web site for showcasing Yanmar's line of commercial and residential tractors at yanmartractor.com. Connected to client product data sourced dynamically from a proprietary product management system. Full stack developer utilizing **ASP.Net MVC**, **Entity Framework**, **Razor**, and **Less**.

VF Imagewear Brand Sites

Implemented responsive, desktop and mobile brand marketing sites for redkap.com, redkapautomotive.com, bulwark.com, and horacesmall.com. Acted as full stack developer using **ASP.Net MVC** and **MS SQL Server** on the back end, with **JavaScript**, **jQuery**, **Less**, and **Razor** on the front end. Responsible for overseeing long-term maintenance and enhancements.

Software Developer, Deloitte Consulting July 2012 - July 2013

Developer on numerous projects for various platforms, including mobile, web, and enterprise. Responsible for making technical and design decisions collaboratively in an **agile** environment. Focus on robust server code and responsive, attractive UI.

Projects

<u>IdeaSummit</u>

Built a social platform where users can share and build upon their ideas in a collaborative way. Users can post ideas and receive community feedback, with the goal of developing their ideas into actual projects. Worked with an agile team as a **full stack developer** using **ASP.Net** and **MS SQL Server**. Implemented a tagging system and built the front end using **JavaScript** and **CSS**.

Roman Kitchen

Created a **hybrid mobile app** that allows users to make reservations and order at their favorite restaurants. Collaborated with a local team as well as distributed and outsourced developers to create a user-friendly experience using **PhoneGap** and **jQuery Mobile**. Functioned as lead client-side developer, and assisted with **architecture** and **deployments**.

JIEDDO

Contract for the Department of Defense

Built a collaboration tool that allowed soldiers and field officers to report and share information on the location or suspected whereabouts of improvised explosive devices (IEDs). Worked as a front end developer and used **JavaScript**, **jQuery** and **CSS** to customize and enhance the interactivity of the SharePoint platform.

Research Assistant, University of Southern Mississippi August 2010 - July 2012

Worked as a programmer in a computer science research lab creating 3D graphics for the web browser. Helped create a simulation and gaming engine using **JavaScript** and **WebGL**.

Projects

OSBEST

Created a fun and engaging game to walk patients at rehabilitation clinics through the Twelve Step program. Built a scripting engine for supporting interactive game content. Assisted with game design and art. Replaced a legacy C++ server with **Node.js** and **Socket.io** for better maintainability.

BIM for Army Corps of Engineers

Created a web application that allows users to participate collaboratively in virtual walkthroughs of buildings before construction begins. Ten to fifteen users are able to simultaneously annotate the environment in order to provide feedback to architects and builders.